National Visionary Leadership Project Interviews and Conference Collection AFC 2004/007
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series III: Interviews
  - Edward Martin oral history interview conducted by Cleandria Chevalier, 2005-10-20, AFC 2004/007: 193
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 193.MV.001
  - Gladys Mayo oral history interview conducted by Afra Muhammad, 2003, AFC 2004/007: 194
    Gladys Mayo was a cook, restaurant owner and civic leader.
    The interview includes Gladys Mayo's memories of growing up in North Carolina, moving to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and working as a cook. She recalls opening her own restaurant called Granny's Place, starting a community garden and opening a mini-mall for small minority-owned businesses. She discusses her volunteer work with women in prison, raising foster children and starting a food pantry.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655278
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (32 pages) (Box-folder 17/215)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 194.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 194.MV.002
  - Mary McEwan oral history interview conducted by Jocelyn I. Cole, 2006, AFC 2004/007: 195
    Mary McEwan was a caterer, restaurant owner and cookbook writer.
    The interview includes Mary McEwan's memories of growing up in Alabama and Nashville, Tennessee, attending Tennessee State University and marrying her husband. She recalls starting her catering business and barbeque restaurant, and cooking at several universities in Nashville. She discusses writing poetry and cookbooks, her involvement at the Spruce Street Baptist Church and volunteering with the Bethlehem Center.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655280
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (72 pages) (Box-folder 17/216)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 195.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 195.MV.002
  - Sara McKissick oral history interview conducted by Eric Majette, Jr, 2005-09-23, AFC 2004/007: 196
    Sara McKissick was a gospel singer who performed with the Lucy Smith Singers.
    The interview includes Sara McKissick's memories of growing up in Atlanta, Georgia, attending Clark University and moving to Chicago, Illinois. She recalls learning gospel music at church and performing with the Lucy Smith Singers and the Caravans. She discusses her friendship with Roberta Martin, the influence of other gospel singers on her work and the future of gospel music.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655281
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (22 pages) (Box-folder 17/217)
    - Graphic Images, 4 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/472)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 196.MV.001
  - Stanley McMullen oral history interview conducted by Lakisha May, 2003, AFC 2004/007: 197
    Stanley McMullen was a teacher and civic leader.
    The interview includes Stanley McMullen's memories of attending the Tuskegee Institute, working with a farm training program, and becoming a high school teacher in Gloucester, Virginia. He recalls teaching vocational courses, sponsoring the Future Farmers of America club, and the integration of public schools. He discusses serving on Gloucester's Equalization Board and Planning Commission and as president of the Middle Peninsula Relief Society.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655282
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (34 pages) (Box-folder 17/218)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (MiniDV) (180 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 197.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 197.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 197.MV.003
  - Bennie McRae oral history interview conducted by Yael Yisrael, 2006-10-15, AFC 2004/007: 198
    Bennie McRae was a historian and employee of the Federal Aviation Administration.
    The interview includes Bennie McRae's memories of growing up in Alabama, experiencing discrimination and segregation, and attending the Tuskegee Institute. He recalls serving in the Air Force during the Korean War, the Montgomery Bus Boycott, and his career with the Federal Aviation Administration. He discusses his interest in African American history and genealogy and starting his website "Lest We Forget" about African Americans who served in the military.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655283
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (59 pages) (Box-folder 17/219)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 198.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 198.MV.002
  - Samuel Mitchell oral history interview conducted by Joshua Mitchell, 2006-10-12, AFC 2004/007: 199
    Samuel Mitchell was a minister at the Rising Sun Baptist Church in Washington, D.C.
    The interview includes Samuel Mitchell's memories of growing up in Edgefield, South Carolina, moving to Washington, D.C. and working as a crane operator. He recalls joining the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), attending the Washington Baptist Seminary after his retirement and becoming a minister. He discusses his work at the Rising Sun Baptist Church and working with young people.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655286
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (33 pages) (Box-folder 17/220)
    - Graphic Images, 6 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/473)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 199.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 199.MV.002
  - Henry Mitchell oral history interview conducted by Lindsay Alexis Young, 2002, AFC 2004/007: 200
    Henry Mitchell was a Baptist minister, writer and professor of theology.
    The interview includes Henry Mitchell's memories of growing up in Columbus, Ohio, attending Ohio State University and his decision to become a minister. He recalls attending Union Seminary where he met his wife, Reverend Ella Mitchell, and serving as chaplain at North Carolina Central University. He discusses his work as a district missionary in California, raising his children, and starting many Christian youth programs.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655285
    - Graphic Images, 2 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/474)
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (33 pages) (Box-folder 17/221)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 200.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 200.MV.002
  - LaVerne Jackson Moore oral history interview conducted by Bianca Robinson, 2006, AFC 2004/007: 201
    LaVerne Jackson Moore was a professor of physical education at Florida A & M University.
    The interview includes LaVerne Jackson Moore's memories of growing up in Cincinnati, Ohio, attending the University of Cincinnati and her first job as a physical education teacher at St. Paul's Polytechnic Institute in Virginia. She recalls meeting her husband, earning her master's degree at Boston University and teaching physical education at Florida A & M University. She also discusses raising her daughter and traveling to Africa.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655287
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (46 pages) (Box-folder 17/222)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 201.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 201.MV.002
  - Samuel Myers oral history interview conducted by Sean Crump, 2006, AFC 2004/007: 202
    Samuel Myers was an economist, professor and president of Bowie State University.
    The interview includes Samuel Myers' memories of growing up in Baltimore, Maryland, attending Morgan State University and serving in the army during World War II. He recalls earning his graduate degrees in economics at Boston University and Harvard University. He recalls working as an economist for the State Department, teaching at Morgan State University and becoming president of Bowie State University. He discusses the university's integration, increasing funding and expanding business education programs.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655288
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (35 pages) (Box-folder 18/223)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 202.MV.001
  - Barbara Oldwine oral history interview conducted by Megan Lollie, 2006-10-16, AFC 2004/007: 203
    Barbara Oldwine was a social worker and civic leader.
    The interview includes Barbara Oldwine's memories of growing up in Binghamton, New York, attending Fisk University and marrying her husband. She recalls moving to Washington, D.C., working at the Pentagon and moving back to Binghamton. She discusses her career at Medicaid, volunteering for the Girl Scouts and the YWCA and her community radio show.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655290
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (39 pages) (Box-folder 18/224)
    - Graphic Images, 2 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/475)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 203.MV.001
  - Anyim Palmer oral history interview conducted by Naomi Young, 2003, AFC 2004/007: 204
    Anyim Palmer was a teacher, principal and the founder of the Marcus Garvey School.
    The interview includes Anyim Palmer's memories of growing up in Texas, serving in the army during World War II and working at the shipyards in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He recalls moving to Los Angeles, California, attending Los Angeles City College and his conversion to Islam. He discusses founding the Marcus Garvey School and his opinions on educating African American children.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655291
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (32 pages) (Box-folder 18/225)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 204.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 204.MV.002
  - Essie Kathryn Payne oral history interview conducted by Reniesha Williams, 2004, AFC 2004/007: 205
    Essie Kathryn Payne was a writer and professor of English at Central State University.
    Essie Kathryn Payne was interviewed in 2004 for the National Visionary Leadership Project by Reniesha Williams, a National Visionary Heritage Fellow, Central State University, in Ohio.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655243
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 205.MV.001
  - Margaret Peters oral history interview conducted by Dominique Squires, 2006, AFC 2004/007: 206
    Margaret Peters was a teacher, historian and civic leader.
    The interview includes Margaret Peters' memories of growing up in Dayton, Ohio, attending the University of Dayton and becoming a teacher. She recalls her efforts to include black history in the Dayton school district's social studies curriculum, her work at the Aviation Heritage Foundation and writing books on African American history. She discusses Dayton's African American history, her volunteer work and her love of poetry.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655292
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (54 pages) (Box-folder 18/227)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 206.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 206.MV.002
  - Frances Pratt oral history interview conducted by Schoquilla Coleman, 2005, AFC 2004/007: 207
    Frances Pratt was a nurse and civil rights activist.
    The interview includes Frances Pratt's memories of growing up in South Carolina, attending Barber-Scotia College and becoming a Seventh Day Adventist. She recalls moving to Nyack, New York, attending nursing school and working at the Nyack Hospital for 46 years. She discusses joining the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), becoming president of its Nyack branch and volunteering at her church.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655295
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (38 pages) (Box-folder 18/228)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 207.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 207.MV.002
  - Bernard Proctor oral history interview conducted by Samira Harris, 2003, AFC 2004/007: 208
    Bernard Proctor was a Tuskegee Airman, professor and Vice President of Cheyney University.
    The interview includes Bernard Proctor's memories of growing up in Pennsylvania and attending Wilberforce University where he played baseball and football. He recalls serving in the army air force during World War II and flying missions in North Africa and Italy. He discusses returning to Wilberforce to coach, attending Ohio State University for graduate school and teaching industrial arts at several historically black colleges and universities.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655297
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (36 pages) (Box-folder 18/229)
    - Graphic Images, 1 photograph: digital, tiff files, color (Box-folder 31/476)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (MiniDV) (180 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 208.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 208.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 208.MV.003
  - Norman Rates oral history interview conducted by Shayla Griffin, 2002, AFC 2004/007: 209
    Norman Rates was a minister and professor of religion at Spelman College.
    The interview includes Norman Rates' memories of growing up in Kentucky, his participation in church and attending Kentucky State College. He recalls attending seminary at Lincoln University and Oberlin Divinity School and becoming the minister of Sisters Chapel at Spelman College. He recalls the changes at Spelman College in the 1960s, teaching classes on women and the Bible, and visiting Africa.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655298
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (25 pages) (Box-folder 18/230)
    - Graphic Images, 1 photograph: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/477)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 209.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 209.MV.002
  - Robert Rivers oral history interview conducted by Jessica Dalton, 2006, AFC 2004/007: 210
    Robert Rivers was a police officer and detective in New York City.
    The interview includes Robert Rivers' memories of growing up in Harlem, New York, serving in the air force and attending Fordham University. He recalls supporting the Schomburg Library, working many odd jobs and meeting his wife. He discusses his career as a police officer in New York, becoming a detective in the street crime unit and his faith.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655299
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (25 pages) (Box-folder 18/231)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 210.MV.001
  - Willieboyd Saddler oral history interview conducted by Jeffrey McLeod, 2006-10-17, AFC 2004/007: 211
    Willieboyd Saddler was an accountant for the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC).
    The interview includes Willieboyd Saddler's memories of growing up in Georgia and attending Fort Valley State College. She discusses her early career in finance and insurance and meeting her husband. She recalls meeting Martin Luther King, Jr., her work as an accountant for the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC) and several events of the civil rights movement.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655474
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (51 pages) (Box-folder 18/232)
    - Graphic Images, 11 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/478)
    - Moving Images, 3 videocassettes of 3 (MiniDV) (180 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 211.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 211.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 211.MV.003
  - Blanche Scott oral history interview conducted by Mark Hanna, 2003-10-19, AFC 2004/007: 212
    Blanche Scott was a nursing assistant and Jamaican immigrant.
    The interview includes Blanche Scott's memories of growing up in Jamaica, moving to England and New York and becoming a nursing assistant. She recalls the death of her husband, raising her children and her work serving the homeless. She discusses her faith and offers advice to young African Americans.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655151
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (25 pages) (Box-folder 18/233)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 212.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 212.MV.002
  - Jessie Carney Smith oral history interview conducted by Karly Campbell, 2005-10-11, AFC 2004/007: 213
    Jessie Carney Smith was a professor, historian and the University Librarian at Fisk University.
    The interview includes Jessie Carney Smith's memories of growing up in North Carolina and attending North Carolina A & T University. She recalls moving to Nashville, Tennessee, working at Fisk University and earning her master's and Ph.D. in library science. She discusses her career as a librarian and professor, writing books on African American history, literature and genealogy and her involvement with United Methodist Women.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655152
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (27 pages) (Box-folder 18/234)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 213.MV.001
  - Charles Snyder oral history interview conducted by Elizabeth Craig, 2005, AFC 2004/007: 214
    Charles Snyder was an employee of the Albion Housing Commission, president of the National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials, and county commissioner in Albion, Michigan.
    Charles Snyder was interviewed for the National Visionary Leadership Project, by Elizabeth Craig, a National Visionary Heritage Fellow, Central State University.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655245
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (4 pages) (Box-folder 18/235)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 214.MV.001
  - Barbara Peek Sternick oral history interview conducted by Qrescent Mali Mason, 2004, AFC 2004/007: 215
    Barbara Peek Sternick was interviewed in 2004 for the National Visionary Leadership Project by Qrescent Mali Mason, a National Visionary Heritage Fellow, Spelman College, in Atlanta, Georgia.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655303
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 215.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 215.MV.002
  - Edward S. Temple oral history interview conducted by Kenneth Thompson, 2002-10-16, AFC 2004/007: 216
    Edward Temple was a track coach for the U.S. women's Olympic team and at Tennessee State University.
    The interview includes Edward Temple's memories of growing up in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, playing sports and attending Tennessee State University where he ran track. He recalls meeting his wife, coaching the Tennessee State University women's track team and urging the university to award scholarships for women athletes. He discusses segregation in sports, coaching the women's Olympic track team and the results of Title IX to increase funding for women's sports.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655154
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (51 pages) (Box-folder 18/237)
    - Graphic Images, 2 photographs: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/479)
    - Moving Images, 1 videocassette of 1 (MiniDV) (60 min.) sound, color; 1/2 in. camera master; 1 videocassette of 1 (DVC) (186 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 216.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 216.MV.002
  - Delores Tillman oral history interview conducted by Christopher Carr, 2005-11-02, AFC 2004/007: 217
    Delores Tillman was a nursing assistant and hospice care worker.
    The interview includes Delores Tillman's memories of growing up in Baltimore, Maryland, working as an elevator operator and raising her family. She recalls the riots of 1968, her career as a nursing assistant at St. Agnes Hospital and facing discrimination from supervisors. She discusses her work in hospice home care and her involvement with the Faith Tabernacle Church.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655156
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (30 pages) (Box-folder 10/238)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.): sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 217.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 217.MV.002
  - Billye Von Blasingame oral history interview conducted by Alondra Young, 2006-10-28, AFC 2004/007: 218
    Billye Von Blasingame was a teacher, counselor and the dean of students at the University of the District of Columbia.
    The interview includes Billye Von Blasingame's memories of growing up in Alabama, attending Spelman College and becoming a teacher. She recalls moving to California, her struggles to find a job as a teacher, and becoming a guidance counselor. She discusses her involvement in the civil rights movement and the Mississippi freedom rides.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655157
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (53 pages) (Box-folder 18/239)
    - Moving Images, 2 videocassettes of 2 (MiniDV) (120 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 218.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 218.MV.002
  - Frances Walker-Slocum oral history interview conducted by Heather Griffin, 2002-11-02, AFC 2004/007: 219
    Frances Walker-Slocum was a pianist and music professor at Oberlin College.
    Frances Walker-Slocum was interviewed on November 2, 2002 for the National Visionary Leadership Project by Heather Griffin, a National Visionary Heritage Fellow, Oberlin College, in Oberlin, Ohio.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2011655246
    - Graphic Images, 1 photograph: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/480)
    - Moving Images, 4 videocassettes of 4 (MiniDV) (240 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 219.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 219.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 219.MV.003; AFC 2004/007: 219.MV.004
  - DeLois Wilkinson oral history interview conducted by Kenny L. Robinson, Jr, 2003, AFC 2004/007: 220
    DeLois Wilkinson was a physical therapist, teacher and civil rights activist.
    The interview includes DeLois Wilkinson's memories of growing up in Arkansas, attending LeMoyne College and Northwestern University, and becoming a physical therapist. She recalls joining the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), working with disabled children and the integration of Nashville, Tennessee public schools. She discusses serving on the Nashville school board, her opinions on the education of African American children and her memories of civil rights protests in Nashville.
    Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010655159
    - Manuscripts, 1 transcript (91 pages) (Box-folder 18/241)
    - Graphic Images, 1 photograph: digital, jpeg files, color (Box-folder 31/481)
    - Moving Images, 4 videocassettes of 4 (MiniDV) (240 min.) sound, color; 1/4 in. camera master; AFC 2004/007: 220.MV.001; AFC 2004/007: 220.MV.002; AFC 2004/007: 220.MV.003; AFC 2004/007: 220.MV.004
  - Frances Williams oral history interview conducted by Kristian Ali, 2006, AFC 2004/007: 221
    Frances Williams was a teacher and guidance counselor.